Inventory of the James Wei diaries
Hoover Institution Archives
James Wei diaries
1959-1982
2003C19
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box, 14 oversize boxes (9.3 linear feet)
Relates to political conditions in Taiwan, and to Taiwanese-American relations.
Wei, James.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2003.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
James Wei was a Taiwanese writer. A native of Chekiang, Wei graduated from Yenching University in Peking. He started his career as a reporter in Tientsin and later worked in Shanghai. From 1942-1948, he joined the International Department, Ministry of Information.
Wei then became head of the Shanghai Office of the Ministry of Information (later called the Government Information Office). He then settled in Taiwan, where he served as a Reuters correspondent for three years, while simultaneously holding the post of Deputy Director of the Central News Agency. Wei was also one of the founders of the China News, an English language newspaper, along with being the publisher when it was first created in 1949. From 1954-1965, Wei worked as Managing Director of the Broadcasting Corporation of China (BCC). In 1966, he was appointed Director General of the Government Information Office before becoming the Director of the CNA in 1972, before retiring from the CNA in 1978. He was also national policy advisor to President Chiang Ching-kuo until Wei died of a heart attack in October 1982 at the age of 74.
Scope and Content of Collection
This collection relates to political conditions in Taiwan and to Taiwanese-American relations between the years of 1959 and 1982. Diaries written by James Wei detail political conditions across that span of time, as well as his reactions to current events. Wei also kept track of daily events, including descriptions of his conversations with various people and the different activities he engaged in. A small collection of notes contains contact information for other people, as well as other accounts of his aquaintances. A datebook details events Wei presumably attended and reminders about such events that he wrote for himself. There is also correspondence, including notes and a letter addressed to Wei from the Chinese News Service of New York.
Taiwan--Foreign relations--United States.; Taiwan--Politics and government--1945-; United States--Foreign relations--Taiwan.
- Diaries, 1960-1982
  - May-June, 1960 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - July, 1960 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - August, 1960 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - September, 1960 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - October, 1960 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - November, 1960 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - December, 1960 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - January, 1961 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - February, 1961 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - March, 1961 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - April, 1961 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - May, 1961 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - June, 1961 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - July, 1961 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - August, 1961 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - September, 1961 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - October, 1961 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - November, 1961 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - December, 1961 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - January, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - February, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - March, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - April, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - May, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - June, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - July, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - August, 1962, Volume I (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - August, 1962, Volume II (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - September, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - October, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - November, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - December, 1962 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - January, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - February, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - March, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - April, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - May, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - June, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - July, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - August, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - September, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - October, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - November, 1963 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - December, 1963 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - January, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - February, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - March, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - April, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - May, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - June, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - July, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - August, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - September, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - October, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - November, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - December, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - January, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - March, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - April, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - May, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - June, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - July, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - August, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - September, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - October, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - November, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - December, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - January, 1966 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - February, 1966 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - March, 1966 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - April, 1966 (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - May, 1966 (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - June, 1966 (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - July, 1966 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - August, 1966 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - September, 1966 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - October, 1966 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - November, 1966 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - December, 1966 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - January, 1967 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - February, 1967 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - March, 1967 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - April, 1967 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - May, 1967 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - June, 1967 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - July, 1967 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - August, 1967 (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - September, 1967 (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - October, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - November, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - December, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - January, 1968 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - February, 1968 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - March, 1968 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - April, 1968 (Box-folder 7: 7)
  - June, 1968 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - July, 1968 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - August, 1968 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - September, 1968 (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - October, 1968 (Box-folder 7: 12)
  - November, 1968 (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - January, 1969 (Box-folder 7: 14)
  - February, 1969 (Box-folder 7: 16)
  - March, 1969 (Box-folder 7: 17)
  - April, 1969 (Box-folder 7: 18)
  - May, 1969 (Box-folder 7: 19)
  - June, 1969 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - July, 1969 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - August, 1969 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - September, 1969 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - October, 1969 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - November, 1969 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - December, 1969 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - January, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - February, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - March, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - April, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - May, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - June, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 13)
  - July, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 14)
  - August, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 15)
  - September, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 16)
  - October, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 17)
  - November, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 18)
  - December, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 19)
  - January, 1971 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - February, 1971 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - March, 1971 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - April, 1971 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - May, 1971 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - June, 1971 (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - July, 1971 (Box-folder 9: 7)
  - August, 1971 (Box-folder 9: 8)
  - September, 1971 (Box-folder 9: 9)
  - October, 1971 (Box-folder 9: 10)
  - November, 1971 (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - December, 1971 (Box-folder 9: 12)
  - January, 1972 (Box-folder 9: 13)
  - February, 1972 (Box-folder 9: 14)
  - March, 1972 (Box-folder 9: 15)
  - April, 1972 (Box-folder 9: 16)
  - May, 1972 (Box-folder 9: 17)
  - June, 1972 (Box-folder 9: 18)
  - July, 1972 (Box-folder 9: 19)
  - August, 1972 (Box-folder 9: 20)
  - September, 1972 (Box-folder 9: 21)
  - October, 1972 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - November, 1972 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - December, 1972 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - January, 1973 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  - February, 1973 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - March, 1973 (Box-folder 10: 6)
  - April, 1973 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - May, 1973 (Box-folder 10: 8)
  - June, 1973 (Box-folder 10: 9)
  - July, 1973 (Box-folder 10: 10)
  - August, 1973 (Box-folder 10: 11)
  - September, 1973 (Box-folder 10: 12)
  - October, 1973 (Box-folder 10: 13)
  - November, 1973 (Box-folder 10: 14)
  - December, 1973 (Box-folder 10: 15)
  - January, 1974 (Box-folder 10: 16)
  - February, 1974 (Box-folder 10: 17)
  - March, 1974 (Box-folder 10: 18)
  - April, 1974 (Box-folder 10: 19)
  - May, 1974 (Box-folder 10: 20)
  - June, 1974 (Box-folder 10: 21)
  - July, 1974 (Box-folder 10: 22)
  - August, 1974 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - September, 1974 (Box-folder 11: 2)
  - October, 1974 (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - November, 1974 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - December, 1974 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - January, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - February, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - March, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 8)
  - April, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 9)
  - May, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 10)
  - June, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 11)
  - July, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 12)
  - August, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 13)
  - September, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 14)
  - October, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 15)
  - November, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 16)
  - December, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 17)
  - January, 1976 (Box-folder 11: 18)
  - February, 1976 (Box-folder 11: 19)
  - March, 1976 (Box-folder 11: 20)
  - April, 1976 (Box-folder 11: 21)
  - May, 1976 (Box-folder 11: 22)
  - June, 1976 (Box-folder 11: 23)
  - July, 1976 (Box-folder 11: 24)
  - August, 1976 (Box-folder 11: 25)
  - September, 1976 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - October, 1976 (Box-folder 12: 2)
  - November, 1976 (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - December, 1976 (Box-folder 12: 4)
  - January, 1977 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - February, 1977 (Box-folder 12: 6)
  - March, 1977 (Box-folder 12: 7)
  - April, 1977 (Box-folder 12: 8)
  - May, 1977 (Box-folder 12: 9)
  - June, 1977 (Box-folder 12: 10)
  - July, 1977 (Box-folder 12: 11)
  - August, 1977 (Box-folder 12: 12)
  - September, 1977 (Box-folder 12: 13)
  - October, 1977 (Box-folder 12: 14)
  - November, 1977 (Box-folder 12: 15)
  - December, 1977 (Box-folder 12: 16)
  - January, 1978 (Box-folder 12: 17)
  - February, 1978 (Box-folder 12: 18)
  - March, 1978 (Box-folder 12: 19)
  - April, 1978 (Box-folder 12: 20)
  - May, 1978 (Box-folder 12: 21)
  - June, 1978 (Box-folder 12: 22)
  - July, 1978 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - August, 1978 (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - September, 1978 (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - October, 1978 (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - November, 1978 (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - December, 1978 (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - January, 1979 (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - February, 1979 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - March, 1979 (Box-folder 13: 9)
  - April, 1979 (Box-folder 13: 10)
  - May, 1979 (Box-folder 13: 11)
  - June, 1979 (Box-folder 13: 12)
  - July, 1979 (Box-folder 13: 13)
  - August, 1979 (Box-folder 13: 14)
  - September, 1979 (Box-folder 13: 15)
  - October, 1979 (Box-folder 13: 16)
  - November, 1979 (Box-folder 13: 17)
  - December, 1979 (Box-folder 13: 18)
  - January, 1980 (Box-folder 13: 19)
  - February, 1980 (Box-folder 13: 20)
  - March, 1980 (Box-folder 13: 21)
  - April, 1980 (Box-folder 13: 22)
  - May, 1980 (Box-folder 13: 23)
  - June, 1980 (Box-folder 13: 24)
  - July, 1980 (Box-folder 13: 25)
  - August, 1980 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - September, 1980 (Box-folder 14: 2)
  - October, 1980 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  - November, 1980 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - December, 1980 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - January, 1981 (Box-folder 14: 6)
  - February, 1981 (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - March, 1981 (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - April, 1981 (Box-folder 14: 9)
  - May, 1981 (Box-folder 14: 10)
  - June, 1981 (Box-folder 14: 11)
  - July, 1981 (Box-folder 14: 12)
  - August, 1981 (Box-folder 14: 13)
  - September, 1981 (Box-folder 14: 14)
  - October, 1981 (Box-folder 14: 15)
  - November, 1981 (Box-folder 14: 16)
  - December, 1981 (Box-folder 14: 17)
  - February, 1982 (Box-folder 14: 18)
  - Fecruary, 1982 (Box-folder 14: 19)
  - March, 1982 (Box-folder 14: 20)
  - April, 1982 (Box-folder 14: 21)
  - May, 1982 (Box-folder 14: 22)
  - June, 1982 (Box-folder 14: 23)
  - July, 1982 (Box-folder 14: 24)
  - August, 1982 (Box-folder 14: 25)
  - September, 1982 (Box-folder 14: 26)
  - October, 1982 (Box-folder 14: 27)
  - Diary Envelopes, 1959-1982 (Box-folder 15: 8)
    Scope and Contents note
    Example of envelopes used to store diaries.
- Correspondence, 1959, undated (Box-folder 15: 6-7)
- Datebook, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 15: 5)
- Notes, undated (Box-folder 15: 1-4)